Samuel Bailey

Personal Info

Phone:

(409) 920-3313

Email:

s.baileyy@icloud.com

Address

3210 Driftwood Meadow Ln, Richmond TX 77406

Skills

Linux/Unix Shell



GCP/AWS



WordPress



Googling



Golang



C/C++



Python



Education

Southern New Hampshire University, Manchester, New Hampshire

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science, Oct. 2021

Southern New Hampshire University, Manchester, New Hampshire

Master of Information Technology, Cybersecurity Dec. 2022

Certifications

GCP Professional Cloud Architect

GCP Cloud Badge Manage Resources

Professional Summary

Analytical, accomplished, professional Analyst and Developer with over 4 years of experience in multifaceted roles requiring project management, business development, and solution architecture. Skilled in the areas of agile development, DevOps delivery, & enterprise networking. Motivated and eager to advance my career with a growth-oriented, technological-advanced organization.

Employment history

Site Reliability Engineer, YouVersion. Edmond, Oklahoma Mar. 2021 – April. 2022

- Developed system engineering, software engineering, system integration, and distrusted system architectures.
- Collaborate with engineers or software developers to select appropriate design solutions or ensure the compatibility of system components.
- Research, test, and verify proper functioning of software patches and fixes.
- Train system users in system operations and maintenance.
- Verify stability, interoperability, portability, security, or scalability of system architecture.
- Document design specifications, installation instructions, and other system-related information.

Computer Science Instructor, Southern New Hampshire University. Manchester, New Hampshire

Apr. 2021 - Present

- Advise students on academic and vocational curricula and career issues.
- Collaborate with colleagues to address teaching and research issues.
- Supervise undergraduate and graduate teaching, internship, and research work.
- Participate in student recruitment, registration, and placement activities.
- Serve on academic and administrative committees that deal with institutional policies, departmental matters, and academic issues.

Technology Director, Triumph Church. Nederland, Texas Aug. 2017 - Mar. 2021

- Control the lights and sound of events, such as live concerts, before and after performances, and during intermissions.
- Maintain permanent fleet of cryptologic and carry-on direct support systems required in special land, sea surface and subsurface operations.
- Design database applications, such as interfaces, data transfer mechanisms, global temporary tables, data portions, and function-based indexes to enable efficient access of the generic database structure.
- Participate in design and production of multimedia campaigns, handling budgeting and scheduling, and assisting with such responsibilities as production coordination, background design and progress tracking.
- Monitor the performance of project team members, providing and documenting performance feedback.
- Perform systems analysis and programming tasks to maintain and control the use of computer systems software as a systems programmer.